welcome back
Marquez in a
minute hey welcome back to screen Crush
I'm Colton urn and these are all of the
Easter eggs references and little things
you might have missed in sance season 2
episode 1 so we're going to break down
all of the Hidden clues in this episode
about what Lumen is really up to we're
also going to take a look at the final
shot of the episode featuring Miss Casey
on the testing floor we're going to talk
about who the hell this guy lurking in
the hallway is we'll explain Cold Harbor
and how it connects to the Civil War and
the origins of lumen and and and we will
get into our theory that hel R has yet
to return and that this is 100% her Audi
Helena Egan daughter of the Lumen CEO
pretending to be her any heli and guys
by the way we have this great praise
cier sticky note shirt up on the merch
store right now screencrush merch.com
get yours now so it has been a long 3
years since the season one finale and I
have been eagerly awaiting its return in
fact one of the first screen crush
videos I ever watched was Ryan's ending
explain for the first season and that's
actually what turned me on to this show
this series is a modern-day masterclass
in how to make television in the
streaming age and a reminder on how
truly great television can be when
storytelling is given the proper time
and attention that it deserves Severance
is essentially a workplace dark comedy
with a science fiction bent and it's
it's really a brilliant commentary on
the employee employer relationship in
our modern era so season 1 ended with
Mark heli Dylan and Irving bucking the
system and finally standing up against
their oppressors Dylan sneaks into the
security office and activates the
overtime contingency allowing for Mark
heli and Irving to wake up on the
outside Irving went to find his beloved
Bert heli wakes up at the Lumen Gala
realizing that her Audi is bad news and
an Egan and Mark wakes up at his
brother-in-law Rick's reading party for
his book The U are remember Mark and the
others have become fans of ricken on the
inside after finding and reading his
book in the office now at this party
Mark guest learns that his Audi
underwent the severance procedure
following the death of his wife but Mark
s the in recognizes his Audi's late wife
as health and wellness counselor Miss
Casey so season 2 opens with audio from
the season 1
finale they tortur us down there D we're
prisoners we hear heli telling the crowd
at the luming gala that they are not
happy down on the SED floor we can hear
Irving screaming bird's name and banging
on his front door and of course Mark
yelling she's alive so when Mark arrives
back on the severed floor he is awaking
for the first time since being on the
outside according to Mr milch it's been
5 months since the MDR Uprising and guys
the filmmaker and me has to give this
show serious props for it's super
creative cinematography I love the push
Zoom technique that they do to create
the focal length change demonstrating
the transition between in's and Audi's
and this continuous shot of Mark Tom
Cruising through the Halls is yet
another great example of the top-notch
cinematography and attention to detail
that they have on this show so as Mark
runs through the Halls we see him past
this purple themed room that we actually
saw here in season 1 and a little later
we hear that the new Refiner's old MDR
office was also purple but I love the
Green carpet ours was a crem and the
keyboards were puse they were purple so
Mark makes his way to the Health and
Wellness Center to find Miss Casey when
entering the waiting room to the Health
and Wellness Center we can see that the
doors to her office have been completely
removed and if you look here behind Mark
we can see an outline on the wall where
this painting from season 1 used to hang
the painting that we saw Irving and Bert
admiring the first time they met in this
scene now that's not the only thing
behind Mark we also have this guy
lurking in the background but we're
going to talk about that here in a sec
so when Mark arrives in the MDR office
we can see this trinket on one of the
desks likely a perk won by this employee
for his previous refining work in
another MDR milch then arrives wearing a
blue turtleneck and carrying these blue
balloons with Mark's face on them here
in a sec I want to tell you just how
disturbing the symbolism Behind These
balloons is but first let's talk about
the significance of the color blue in
this series and this episode
specifically and how it connects to the
war between the severed employees and
their oppressors like like Miss coobel
Mr milch and Helena Egan essentially the
color blue down on the severed floor is
representing calm while simultaneously
being connected to control the color
blue can be comforting and that's what
they're trying to do make the enies feel
calm comfortable and at peace so that
they may do their work but the color
blue is also associated with the higher
ups like Miss cabel and now with Mr
milch and even on heli R Who on the
outside is of course Helena Egan the
color blue is also seen all over the
severed floor such as the computers and
even being the primary color we see many
of the Sate employees wearing again
representing calm and control so next we
meet Miss Wong who is disturbingly a
child Miss Wong's position is that of
Deputy manager and this is her first day
in this new role prior to that she was a
crossing guard so my first question was
why are you a child but I also found
myself wondering where the hell were you
a crossing guard I mean what is going on
in the depths of lumen that called for a
crossing guard but like I said The more
disturbing question is why is there a
child working at Lumen on the severed
floor a child should be at school during
the day not working a job I also don't
think that she's unsaved like milch and
gets to go home every day I think like
Miss Casey and like employees that pety
mentioned in season 1 she never leaves I
found a
department one they don't tell us us
about one where you don't get to leave
the only scenario in which I can imagine
a child working at Lumen and that
actually being allowed would only be in
a situation like with Miss Casey where
up in the outer world Miss Wong is dead
so here in a bit I want to share our
theory on what the hell is going on at
Lumen and how it all connects to a quest
for immortality and the resurrection of
Kier and I think Miss Wong Miss Casey
and even this dude lurking in the
hallway behind Mark will give us our
answer but first let's take a look at a
few more Det details from this episode
that contribute to our working theory in
milch's office we see this newspaper
called The Cure Chronicle at the top of
the paper it says published since 1893
that's 28 years after the founding of
lumen keep that in mind it's going to
come back into play here in a sec in
this corner here it reads your trusted
source for going on in Kier and the
greater World remember that our Audi do
live in the town of Kier so it's also
here on the paper that we can see this
Photoshop picture featuring the team
photo from season 1 placing the team
into an old school convertible at what
looks like a parade under the picture it
reads here Lumen employees were
celebrated on Sunday for exposing the
nature of severed work now milch
presents this paper as if it's in
circulation on the surface and they even
went through the trouble of redacting a
lot of the text on the page with a
sharpie but I actually think we're meant
to take this as yet another manipulation
trying to trick the enies into thinking
that their Audi are being celebrated on
the outside for their in work
contributing to the theme of in's being
told they're happy on the outside out
side and that an in's role is to serve
their outer self so it's clear that
Lumen is doing your classic apology tour
that we see corporations in our real
world do when they're busted doing bad
stuff they're putting on this facade to
the outer world and to the Ines below
that they have learned from their
mistakes and that they are grateful for
the opportunity to become a better
company when in reality it's all just
damage control it's PR bull okay so now
let's talk about these balloons I love
the imagery of having Mark's head on a
balloon one it's a mirroring of the
visual focal length change we see in the
elevator when Mark switches between his
inie and his Audi this visualization
makes the head look like it's actually
being inflated with air like a balloon
the same thing would happen with the
image of Mark's face on the balloons as
air is added or removed the picture
would stretch I also really love this
shot in the hall when Mark releases the
balloons and we see them float to the
ceiling but they are blocked by the
ceiling from ascending any higher just
like the consciousness of an any is
unable to ascend beyond the severed
floor that is of course without enabling
the overtime protocol now this shot of
the balloons is brilliantly symbolizing
how Mark is desperate to leave this
place and crawl his way out of the
severed floor next we have the pass the
ball game here we see a red ball passed
around as a team building exercise now
this red ball could be in reference to
the popular red ball Theory as well as
the ball in the Box analogy both of
those essentially use a red ball to
demonstrate emotions like grief or
anxiety both both of which Mark s is
suffering from Red also of course
symbolizes emotions such as rage but
also love Mark heli Irving and Dylan are
all experiencing great rage but rage
that is triggered by separation from
something they love Mark has the
knowledge that his wife from the Audi
world is thought to be dead but is
actually alive and being held captive by
Lumen heli wants freedom and now knows
that her Audi is an Egan Dylan wants to
know his family and Irving wants to be
with Bert all of them have love in their
hearts that is being stomped out by
Lumen causing rage now next we hear
mention of the perpetuity Wing what's
your perpetuity Wing like you'll
remember in season 1 that we saw the
team travel to the perpetuity Wing which
was of course suggested by Irving to
help heli find her meaning at Lumen
there we saw these wax figures of all
the Lumen CEOs but we learned that in
these new workers former perpetuity Wing
they say that their Egans were
animatronic meaning that they could move
and they conclude that this must mean
that Marx has wax figures instead of
animatronics because their wing is older
now here we also hear Dario say that in
his former workplace instead of an
elevator they had a rope now in Mark's
funny note about milch we hear mention
of the nine core principles a man who
stupidity is rivaled only by that of the
nine core principles the nine core
principles are Vision Verve wit cheer
humility benevolence nimbleness probity
and WS these principles are of course
part of lum's cult-like manipulation of
their employees which is symbolic of
corporate rule but it is also a
commentary on organized religion echoing
the Seven Virtues Of Catholicism and
these two even share the rule of
humility I also think that these nine
principles could also be in connection
to Dante's Inferno and the nine circles
of hell and I'm going to dive deep into
all of that here shortly so next we find
out that despite Mark having woken up to
the realities of lumen and we see that
Mark has become a true Rebel however he
is still very naive I say this because
we see him plead to the board I know
that you want to do the right thing for
severed people which is why I need to
see my team again you'd think by this
point mark would know that the board is
likely even worse than the likes of
milch and coell it's the board even
there yes okay so after Mar s shows that
he will not comply and he will not be a
reliable employee until he sees his team
again we see The Return of Irving heli
and Dylan but before they return we get
this creepy ass paint called Kier
pardons his betrayers in this painting
we see Kier in what looks like a union
uniform from the American Civil War and
this is actually connected to Cold
Harbor the project that macro dat
refinement is working on with the scary
numbers behind cier in this painting we
can see an army of men carrying rifles
that have bayonets attached and kir is
pardoning four people who are buried
shoulder deep these four heads sticking
out of the ground symbolize the enies
having poked their heads up beyond the
surface of the underground SE floor
tying into the theme of Mark's head on
the balloon trying to poke his head out
into the above world now being buried
neck deep in the ground also symbolizes
the stressful emotions and feeling of
being trapped one can feel when
overwhelmed especially regarding their
job which of course this entire series
is essentially an allegory for work life
balance feeling trapped in a career and
barely being able to keep your head
above water now you'll also notice that
on kier's sword there's blood on the
blade so Dylan is the first to return
and he immediately talks about how milch
had tackled him referring to this scene
in the season 1 finale just open the
door and I'll tell you their names come
on Dylan but something actually stuck
out to me here the last thing Dylan
remembered wouldn't be being tackled by
milch Dylan was still on the severed
floor when the overtime lever switch
back meaning that Dylan's inie was still
present following his tackling so I'm
anxious to know what happened after
milch tackled him to the ground it
sounds to me like Dylan wasn't at Lumen
much longer following his t down now
when Irving arrives we hear him banging
on the elevator doors screaming Bert
this is because the last time we saw him
he was at Bert's house banging on the
door screaming his name and then there's
the return of heli r or should I say
Helena that's right I don't think for a
second that this is actually heli R I
think this is Helena and that she is in
full control and acting as if she is
heli R we actually got a hint at this
being the case later in the episode when
she lies about what she saw when she
woke up on the outside I saw the inside
of a
really boring apartment now at first I
thought that heli must just be ashamed
of the fact that she's an Egan and maybe
she even feared what her friend's
response would be to learning who her
Audi really is but heli just doesn't
strike me as the type to hide this type
of Revelation and Helena doesn't strike
me as the type that would allow heliar
to return and that's why I think that
heli is really Helena undercover I think
that Helena has seen to it that her
severed inhibitor be shut off or
disabled it's still in her head but just
not currently active and of course we
know that they have the ability to
switch these Inhibitors between
consciousnesses regardless of being on
the severed floor or not so anyway we
see that the break room has been
reformed no longer is it home to the
disturbing apology board I really am
sorry okay now it's a literal break room
where instead of being broken down you
can actually take a break and recuperate
or so they say this room along with its
corporate posters and condescending
cartoon praising the MDR team for their
Uprising it's all reminiscent of when a
company like in the real world gets
busted doing something super shady and
then they come out with their little
apology pretending like they give a damn
about actually doing better we are
deeply sorry we're sorry we're sorry in
this video we hear recorded audio from
season 1 such as Bert saying let's burn
this place to the ground this of course
reminds us that they're always being
watched and listened to now milch does
say privacy shouldn't mean packing into
a Supply Closet like so many sardines
that is in reference to this scene of
course from season 1 if they can wake us
up on the outside what's to stop us from
doing it to ourselves next we get
another clue that heli is actually
Helena when she says he said there were
no microphones in here helar wouldn't
have believed a word out of milch's
mouth so it's clear to me that she is
actually Helena and she is trying to
pull information out of Mark Irving and
Dylan and learn what they did on on the
surface now while I'm pretty confident
that this is Helena there are certain
moments that make me wonder if it could
actually be heli such as her telling
Irvin that it's okay to tell them what
he saw up there even if it was bad this
moment and that look on her face implies
that heli is referring to her own hidden
and shameful Discovery but I think we
might actually be seeing Helena feeling
a little guilty for her role in all of
this and that she is just being
manipulative and trying to find out what
they saw up there there's also this
scene we're not not the same actually Us
in the AIS were're not but I still think
that this is actually Helena having a
disdain for her in heli and that's why
it seems so genuine because she is
trying to convince herself that what
she's doing is right and that what
they're doing to the enies is not
immoral but I think deep down she knows
that it is okay so next we see Miss Wong
playing with a toy where you try to get
these little rings around the hands of a
swimming cure the Rings are red blue and
green like the red blue and green lights
on this projector in the break room and
the red blue and green paper in the
Supply Closet now her playing this game
is likely meant to remind us that
despite her acting like an adult Miss
Wong is still a child Irving goes on to
tell Dylan that the paintings of a black
hallway with a red down pointing Arrow
the same elevator that we saw Miss Casey
taken to in the season one finale
remember Irving's Audi is the one
painting all of these pictures of that
same elevator and in season 1 we also
saw Irving having trouble staying awake
at work and he would see the black ooze
coming onto his desk this all implies
that Irving has been down to the testing
floor before but he doesn't remember it
okay so let's finally get into the Cold
Harbor of it all so at the end of the
episode we see Mark working on his scary
numbers and at the top of the screen it
reads Colt Harbor so I did some Googling
and Colt Harbor is a battle from the
American Civil War that took place in
1864 one year before the founding of
lumen now the Battle of Cold Harbor was
one where the union got Drax by the
Confederacy in Richmond Virginia in the
spring of 1864 confeder General Robert E
Lee outmaneuvered Union general ulyses
srant and he won the battle remember
earlier in the episode we saw Kier and
what appeared to be a union uniform now
we know of course that the union would
go on to win the war in our reality that
is but I'm beginning to wonder if in
this reality that Severance takes place
in did the war Go a different way I mean
the Civil War was a battle of the states
and in Severance our Audi live in a
state abbreviated PE which isn't a real
state so I think it's possible that they
could be be living in an alternate
timeline with an alternate history I
mean the Civil War was about slavery and
this series is also essentially about
slavery not race-based slavery but
class-based slavery not only how those
in poverty have become essentially slave
labor working at starvation wages but
also how the middle class is given just
enough comfortability to keep them
working hard and generating wealth for
the top it's also worth mentioning that
Mark Scout was once a professor a
history Professor to be ex act a history
Professor whose expertise was World War
I which took place about 50 years after
the American Civil War no one would have
called it World War I cuz World War II
hadn't happened yet Mark's knowledge of
history and war is likely why he was
sought out for this position now it's
also on this screen that we can see a
flash to another screen that also reads
Cold Harbor and features Miss Casey
these graphics on the screen are similar
to the graphics on the bottom of Mark
screen confirming that what Mark is
working on is connected to the testing
that's happening on the floor below and
likely connected directly to miss Casey
and here we can see what looks like
moving cells specifically brain cells I
think it's clear that with all of this
praise cure nonsense this is some kind
of elite cult who is trying to perfect
immortality because there's one thing
that no amount of money can change
there's one thing that you and I have in
common with a billionaire like Elon Musk
and that is the fact that we are all
going to die no amount of money can
result in cheating death and I think
that this Rich oligarch Kier was
unwilling to accept this fate and he
spent his life trying to achieve
immortality and we're seeing that
mission continue over the decades at
Lumen and their mission I believe is to
resurrect Kier Egan and Achieve
immortality for themselves now Lumen
could be trying to perfect cloning but
not just cloning I think they're trying
to perfect the transfer of Consciousness
and that's where the severed and the
study of Consciousness and what it means
to be you comes into play remember
Rick's book is called the you you are
now sure assuming that you master
cloning technology you could clone
yourself before you die but that's still
really not you it's a copy of you your
personal Consciousness still would cease
to exist when you die in your body but
if one could figure out how to transfer
Consciousness instead of merely
duplicating it you could theoretically
Master immortality now in our real World
Consciousness is still something that
modern science doesn't quite have a
grasp on so I think that in this show
that is what Lumen is doing they are
trying to crack the code on
Consciousness what it is and how to
access it as a tangible thing that could
theoretically be Eternal once it is
understood this series is all about what
it means to be you it's a philosophical
analysis of Consciousness we see the
severed employees as a completely clean
slate Consciousness that Lumen controls
and they're tested by literally picking
numbers that they find scary amongst
literal lines of scrolling code I
believe that they are trying to give
tangibility to Consciousness and they
hope to be able to treat Consciousness
like a software my theory is that they
are trying to figure out how to
translate the electrical synapses in the
brain that create Consciousness and
translate it not copy it but transfer it
like software onto new hardware it's
been theorized before that Miss Casey
isn't actually Mark's wife but a clone
of Mark's wife and that could explain
why she unlike the others has such an
odd personality that's almost
otherworldly now when talking to my
friends Harriet and Lee who are video
editors here at screen crush and fellow
Severance fans they both had some
awesome theories on who this man lurking
in the background could be and they are
both tied to this cloning and
Consciousness Theory one possibility is
that it is grener grener had a security
he died in season 1 but what if this guy
lurking in the Halls is a new Grainer
greener's clone doing his job and
monitoring the separate Halls the other
fun theory is that we're having a bit of
a lowkey season 2 moment here and that
the guy sneaking up behind Mark and
watching from the hall is actually Mark
and later this season we could see the
perspective of this other Mark watching
his other self in that Health and
Wellness Center if Lumen is trying to
master immortality they'd need both
cloning Tech to create the bodies but
also the Consciousness Tech that we have
discussed what if their search for the
scary numbers is them essentially
creating a tangible code of their
Consciousness now while in the real
world we have not cracked the the code
on Consciousness we have however kind of
figured out cloning we've actually
cloned a lamb and I think that the goats
that we saw in season one of severant
are test subjects for Lumen cloning Tech
now goats of course also have a
connection to Satanism and I am rather
certain that the severed floor and the
testing floor are meant to represent
hell but not just hell The Nine Circles
of Hell Dante's Inferno and The Nine
Circles of Hell could be being mirrored
by the nine rules of lumen which could
also represent the nine levels of lumen
going deeper and deeper into the ground
that's right I think the severed floor
and the testing floor are just the
second and third levels to an even
deeper evil that evil being Kier in
Dante's Inferno we know that the devil
the Beast himself he is on the bottom
bottom floor so perhaps that's where we
could find the body of kir Egan now I
know that was a lot but that's what I
think is going down and I wanted to put
it out there before seeing the rest of
the season and I cannot wait to watch
these upcoming episodes with you guys
and break them down each week but guys
those were just my thoughts on the first
episode of sant season 2 I want to hear
your thoughts down in the comments below
or you can add me on Twitter or find me
in our Discord Link in the description
below and remember to check out our
praise cure sticky note shirt up on our
merch store right now and if you're new
here please do feel free to subscribe
and smash that Bell for alert so you
don't miss a thing for screen Crush I'm
Colton urn
[Music]